

Ashish Patel Pune/India +917705047900ashishpatel0720@gmail.com

github in linkedin bortfolio

Summary.

Experienced Big Data Engineer with 3.5+ years of total experience in BigData, Java, Scala, and Python seeking to apply my abilities to contribute and build something productive.

I love contributing to Open-source projects and a contributor to Apache Airflow and other Open source projects.

Experience _

Walmart Global Tech

Feb, 2021 - Present / Bangalore, India

Software Engineer III (Big Data)

- Part of the supply chain technology team, and working on cutting edge forecasting solutions to enable the everyday low-cost philosophy of Walmart.
- Building High-Quality Scalable ETL Frameworks to build our Forecasting Pipelines.
- Migrating our On-Prem Hadoop Clusters to Google Cloud Platform as part of a strategic partnership with Google.
- Tech Stack Apache Spark, Java, PySpark, Apache Airflow, GCP DataProc, Bigquery, Astronomer

Deutsche Bank

July, 2018 - Jan, 2021 / Pune, India

Senior Software Engineer

- Worked As a Data engineer in CIB division for Volcker Project.
- We Developed Data pipelines for our Reporting Batch jobs, handling Terabytes of data every day across hundreds of Spark and Hadoop MapReduce ETL jobs.
- Optimized the End to End Pipeline execution time to comply with Regulatory SLA in accordance with new Volcker2.0 regulatory Norms.
- Developed Platform simplification for Informatica jobs using Java8 and Spring + Reactor Framework with Oracle Database.
- Worked on Google Cloud Platform to plan and migrate our On-Premise Cluster and Jobs to GCP.
- Tech Stack Apache Spark, Hadoop MapReduce, Hive, Impala, Beeline, Cloudera CDH, Java, Spring Framework, Spring Boot, Scala, Linux, GCP.

NIT, Bhopal

Oct, 2017 - Feb, 2018 / Bhopal, India

Research Assistant

- Co-written "A Comparative Study of Music Recommendation Systems" with Prof. Rajesh Wadhvani.
- This paper describes different recommendation strategies and compares their practicality on mobile devices.
- Evaluated different Recommendation Strategies by training different ML models and evaluating them.
- ref https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8546852

CarWale.com

May, 2017 - Jul, 2017 / Mumbai, India

Summer Intern

- Worked as Data Engineering Intern in the R&D division of CarWale.
- · We developed CWBigQuery, which is a service that enables interactive analysis of massively large datasets stored in Cassandra Storage.
- It allows users to submit and schedule Spark Job, just using SQL like syntax using Spark SQL.
- This Project took inspiration from Google BigQuery but uses a completely different architecture, we have also created a web application which will provide an interface for users to log in and submit, schedule, and view results.
- TechStack: Scala, Apache Spark, Cassandra, Python-Flask Framework

Education _

NIT, Bhopal 2014 - 2018

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering

• Graduated in Computer Science and Engineering. GGPA - 8.4/10

I.P.S Academy 2011 - 2013

Higher Secondary, Science & Mathematics

 \bullet Completed Higher Secondary with Physics, Chemistry, and Maths. Percentage - 90.2%

Skills _

Programming Java | Scala | Python | C++ | Bash

Big Data Frameworks Apache Spark | Hadoop MapReduce | Apache Airflow | Hive | Impala | Cloudera | Google Cloud | Tensorflow

Software Development Spring Framework | Oracle | MySql | GIT | Agile | DevOps

Languages Native: Hindi | Fluent: English

Awards and Recognition _____

- Competed with 200+ teams and Won 3rd prize in Deutsche Bank's Global DataScience Competition Dabble.
- Won 2nd prize in Hackathon organized by Appointy Inc, https://github.com/pateash/appointy-hackathon
- Winner of Deutsche bank's excellence award.
- Winner of Medhavi Chhatra Puruskar, given by MP State Government for excellent performance in State board exams.

Extra _

- Contributing to Apache Airflow, contributions https://github.com/pateash
- Working on Open source, CMD tool for developers, https://github.com/codingtools/cdt
- Writing Articles on Codebrace on Medium https://medium.com/codebrace, with over 70K+ reads so far.
- Created Opensource Regexplore, Intuitive Regex Checker https://regexplore.github.io